He who holds the sword, rules the world.
Prince Valiant is a adventure, fantasy film directed by Anthony Hickox.
An Arthurian legend of young Prince Valiant, son of the King of Scandia.
After the King is exiled by an evil leader, the Prince travels to Camelot to secure the aid of King
Arthur in helping restore his family to power and prevent a plot by the Black Knight.
Prinz Eisenherz, played by Stephen Moyer.
Princess Ilene, played by Katherine Heigl.
Thagnar, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
King Arthur, played by Edward Fox.
Sligon, played by Udo Kier.
Morgan Le Fey, played by Joanna Lumley.
Prince Valiant is a 1997 independent sword and sorcery film directed by Anthony Hickox, written by Michael Frost Beckner,
and starring Stephen Moyer, Katherine Heigl, Thomas Kretschmann, Joanna Lumley, Ron Perlman, and Edward Fox.
It is a loose adaptation of the long-running Prince Valiant comic strip of
Hal Foster, some panels of which were used in the film.
In it, Valiant must battle the Vikings and a
scheming sorceress to save the kingdom.
The film explores themes of princess, sword,
prince, camelot, vikings (norsemen).